ARMAN DWI PANGESTU

Bandung 40272, West Java | armandwi.pangestu7@gmail.com | https://armandwipangestu.vercel.app

PROFILE

I am an Informatics Engineering student at the University STMIK Bandung. I am a **Junior Web Developer**, **Network Engineer**, **System Administrator**, and **Cloud Engineer** who is passionate about learning the technologies needed to solve problems, I strive to provide an engaging and functional user experience.

EXPERIENCE

PT CITRA JELAJAH INFORMATIKA | SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

JUNE 2023 - OCTOBER 2023

- Install, configure, and maintain DNS (PowerDNS, BIND), Web (Apache, Nginx), Database (MySQL / MariaDB, MongoDB), Mail (Postfix, Dovecot, Roundcube), Monitoring (Grafana, Prometheus, Cacti, PRTG, Zabbix, The Dude) server
- Handle cPanel & CentOS CWP server
- Virtualization management (Proxmox and VMware ESXi)

PT CITRA JELAJAH INFORMATIKA | NETWORK ENGINEER

JUNE 2021 - JUNE 2023

- Analyze, design, and install network needs in buildings, malls, schools, hotels, etc.
- Engineer on Site
- Handle Device Wireless (Ruijie, Ubiquiti / Unifi, TP-Link), Router (Mikrotik, Cisco), Switch Management (Cisco, Arista)
- Work at Network Operation Center (NOC) and Modem Registration using GPON OLT ZTE
- Monitoring Network Traffic using The Dude, Zabbix, Cacti

EDUCATION

BANGKIT ACADEMY 2024 BATCH 1 | CLOUD COMPUTING – DISTINCTION GRADUATE, GRADE 92.56 (A)

FEBRUARY 2024 – JULY 2024

- Handle deployment on Google Cloud Platform project for Capstone Project (Infrastructure, Designing Architecture, Identity Access Management)
- Creating Back-End RESTful API with modern tech stack and secure using Docker, JWT, Zod, etc
- Handle DevOps CI/CD Pipeline on deployment using GitHub Actions to build docker image and deploy to Cloud Run (serverless service or PaaS)

UNIVERSITY STMIK BANDUNG | BACHELOR OF INFORMATICS ENGINEERING, GRADE 3.70

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Software Engineering (Web with PHP, Mobile with Java, Desktop with Visual Basic Programming)
- Database (MySQL / MariaDB, PostgreSQL)
- Microcontroller and Internet of Things (Arduino Uno with C++ Programming)
- Artificial Intelligence (Computer Vision with OpenCV Python)
- Machine Learning (Supervised with Linear Regression, Unsupervised with K-means Clustering, Reinforcement Learning)
- Deep Learning (Convolutional Neural Network with TensorFlow Python)
- Big Data Analytics (Hadoop)

VOCATIONAL HIGH SCHOOL MERDEKA BANDUNG | COMPUTER AND NETWORK ENGINEERING, GRADE 84

2018 - 2021

- Computer (Binary, Hexadecimal, Octal Decimal, RAM, Hardisk, Microsoft Office, Linux)
- Networking (Cabling LAN with Crossover and Straight Through, Subnetting, Routing, Switching, Wireless)

SKILLS & TOOLS

- Programming: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP
- Framework: Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React.js, Express.js, Next.js, Laravel, CodeIgniter
- **Database**: MySQL / MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase, MongoDB
- DevOps / SysAdmin: Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Grafana, Prometheus, Proxmox, VMware, Bash, Apache, Nginx, cPanel, PowerDNS
- Cloud: Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- Networking: Mikrotik, Cisco, Ruijie, Ubiquiti / Unifi
- Microcontroller: Arduino Uno
- Tools: Git, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, GitLab, Figma, Postman, Notion, Trello, Google Colab, Jupyter Notebook